<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>node on kube-prometheus runbooks</title><link>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/</link><description>Recent content in node on kube-prometheus runbooks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefiledescriptorlimit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefiledescriptorlimit/</guid><description>NodeFileDescriptorLimit # Meaning # This alert is triggered when a node&amp;rsquo;s kernel is found to be running out of available file descriptors &amp;ndash; a warning level alert at greater than 70% usage and a critical level alert at greater than 90% usage.
Impact # Applications on the node may no longer be able to open and operate on files. This is likely to have severe consequences for anything scheduled on this node.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefilesystemalmostoutoffiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefilesystemalmostoutoffiles/</guid><description>NodeFilesystemAlmostOutOfFiles # Meaning # This alert is similar to the NodeFilesystemSpaceFillingUp alert, but rather than being based on a prediction that a filesystem will run out of inodes in a certain amount of time, it uses simple static thresholds. The alert will fire as at a warning level at 5% of available inodes left, and at a critical level with 3% of available inodes left.
Impact # A node&amp;rsquo;s filesystem becoming full can have a far reaching impact, as it may cause any or all of the applications scheduled to that node to experience anything from performance degradation to full inoperability.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefilesystemalmostoutofspace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefilesystemalmostoutofspace/</guid><description>NodeFilesystemAlmostOutOfSpace # Meaning # This alert is similar to the NodeFilesystemSpaceFillingUp alert, but rather than being based on a prediction that a filesystem will become full in a certain amount of time, it uses simple static thresholds. The alert will fire as at a warning level at 5% space left, and at a critical level with 3% space left.
Impact # A node&amp;rsquo;s filesystem becoming full can have a far reaching impact, as it may cause any or all of the applications scheduled to that node to experience anything from performance degradation to full inoperability.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefilesystemfilesfillingup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefilesystemfilesfillingup/</guid><description>NodeFilesystemFilesFillingUp # Meaning # This alert is similar to the NodeFilesystemSpaceFillingUp alert, but predicts the filesystem will run out of inodes rather than bytes of storage space. The alert fires at a critical level when the filesystem is predicted to run out of available inodes within four hours.
Impact # A node&amp;rsquo;s filesystem becoming full can have a far reaching impact, as it may cause any or all of the applications scheduled to that node to experience anything from performance degradation to full inoperability.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefilesystemspacefillingup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/nodefilesystemspacefillingup/</guid><description>NodeFilesystemSpaceFillingUp # Meaning # This alert is based on an extrapolation of the space used in a file system. It fires if both the current usage is above a certain threshold and the extrapolation predicts to run out of space in a certain time. This is a warning-level alert if that time is less than 24h. It&amp;rsquo;s a critical alert if that time is less than 4h.
Full context The filesystem on Kubernetes nodes mainly consists of the operating system, container ephemeral storage, container images, and container logs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/noderaiddegraded/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://defenestration.github.io/runbooks/runbooks/node/noderaiddegraded/</guid><description>NodeRAIDDegraded # Meaning # This alert is triggered when a node has a storage configuration with RAID array, and the array is reporting as being in a degraded state due to one or more disk failures.
Impact # The affected node could go offline at any moment if the RAID array fully fails due to further issues with disks.
Diagnosis # You can open a shell on the node and use the standard Linux utilities to diagnose the issue, but you may need to install additional software in the debug container:</description></item></channel></rss>